uh what do you say to those clinics that
Advocate D the right to crush DHD is DHT
detrimental to
longevity what would I say to those
clinics um [__] it like I that's that's
what I'd say like you know I guess each
to their own but that's my opinion
um I would be happy to debate anyone on
this channel live with no preparation
about why we shouldn't be crushing DHD
um it's I I guess it's subject for
argument and discussion but I mean
anyone who understands the role of five
Alpha reduct days not just DHT would
understand the importance of not
suppressing it especially into the
ground with something like oral
dutasteride um so I think that adding
dutasteride to trt not only massively
increases the risk of side effects
because when you block DHT you massively
upregulate conversion to a Rhea
and the it's important that these
enzymes in the body are functioning
naturally and keeping themselves in
homeostasis just like you know blocking
DHT is not good just like blocking
estrogen is not good we need both of
them in Balance um and I think that guys
who and I've said this before and you
know it's of course someone's going to
make the comment that it's two bold guys
talking about this but we're not the
ones who are sacrificing our health
because we're insecure about how pretty
our haircut is is that if people are
knowingly go going to risk sacrificing
their long-term Health to keep their
haircut you don't need to be enabled you
need to speak to someone about that
because that's a uh very concerning
indication of of self-esteem and and
where you're seeking uh validation from
I think that's something that needs to
be looked at quite quite seriously um so
these clinics I mean unfortunately
clinics are going to do whatever they
want and you know upselling multiple
medications is always going to be
appealing but consider that DHT is by
far the strongest Androgen in your body
and if your goal is to increase Androgen
activity via testosterone replacement
therapy this is literally shooting
yourself in the foot but the thing that
guys really need to be conscious of when
it comes to post finasterid syndrome
which you know it falls into dutasteride
as well this is not something that we
know how to fix there are treatments for
it that do work for some guys and a lot
of guys improve but a lot of guys only
get back to 80 90% and plenty of guys
I've met plenty of guys who are still
recovering and they're optimistic but
there's not like a a treatment that we
can go oh if you get PFS take this and
it will fix it this is a unknown and
this is something that you know people
if people don't believe me on this you
can search up the Rooter article for the
lawsuit against the manufacturers of
this drug who knowingly uh suppressed
the information regarding the side
effects that occurred in the clinical
trial they knew about PFS when they were
developing the drug they just didn't
mention it because they knew it would
hurt sales of the the drug they
literally said that in court for the
class action they lost so you know guys
who are still defending this medication
like I I mean I don't know what to say
to people you can take whatever you want
but for for guys who are looking at
getting optimal hormone replacement
therapy care and looking to improve
their hormone levels taking dutasteride
or finasteride is literally the last
thing that you want to do